# DR IHTISHAM MALIK

#### PERSONNEL STATEMENT

My name is Dr. Ihtisham Malik and I am currently working as an Endocrine registrar and UCD Intern and Undergraduate Clinical Tutor at Mullingar Regional hospital with Professor Shu Hoashi and Dr. Ultan Healy. I am pursuing my career in Endocrinology and Diabetes Mellitus

Since graduation, I have been actively engaged in Clinical Medicine and joined the Irish health system in 2014. Besides engagement on the clinical side, I have also focused on the academic side both in terms of teaching and have an excellent record of audit and academic presentations, and that I have already contributed to several publications.

Throughout my career, I have consistently demonstrated excellent communication and interpersonal skills. I am comfortable working in a high pressured environment and either as part of a team dynamic or individually. I am competent in terms of clinical, academic, and clerical skills, and I can effectively communicate with my team, patients, and their families.

My management and leadership skills are participation in endocrine business meetings, participated in UCD undergraduate and interns meetings, rota management skills, lead in teaching and training of medical students, junior doctors and organisation of departmental activities like journal clubs, teaching activities and grand rounds

I am committed to delivering high-standard work and because of my excellent track record I always feel that I would be a great addition to any team/health system and always seeks opportunities to improve my knowledge, professional and personal development

### **QUALIFICATIONS**

2021 Fellowship

Pakistan Society of Internal Medicine

2019 MRCP Ireland

Royal College Of Physicians Of Ireland

2019 MRCPS(G)

Royal College Of Physicians & Surgeons Of Glasgow

2019 MRCP(UK)

Royal College Of Physicians Of United Kingdom

2016 Certificate of Achievement

**HSE-RCPI/CPSP Exchange Programme** 

 Awarded Certificate of Achievement for Completion of IMG training programme

2016 Fellowship training in internal Medicine: GIM

College Of Physicians And Surgeons - Pakistan — Peshawar and Mullingar

Completed Fellowship training in General Internal Medicine (2011-2016).
 completed part of my Fellowship programme in Ireland as CPSP/HSE/RCPI IMG programme

## **CAREER SUMMARY**

# **LOCUM HISTORY**

DATE	GRADE	AREA
3 <sup>rd</sup> & 4 <sup>th</sup> June 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
10 <sup>th</sup> June 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
15 <sup>th</sup> & 18 <sup>th</sup> June 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
25 <sup>th</sup> & 27 <sup>th</sup> June 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
5 <sup>th</sup> & 7 <sup>th</sup> July 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
19 <sup>th</sup> & 21 <sup>st</sup> July 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
27 <sup>th</sup> , 29 <sup>th</sup> July & 1 <sup>st</sup> Aug 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
3 <sup>rd</sup> ,6 <sup>th</sup> ,10 <sup>th</sup> & 12 <sup>th</sup> Aug 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
19 <sup>th</sup> Aug 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
22 <sup>nd</sup> Aug 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
24 <sup>th</sup> Aug 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
2 <sup>nd</sup> Sept 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
21st & 23rd Sept 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
7 <sup>th</sup> Oct 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
5 <sup>th</sup> , 8 <sup>th</sup> , 12 <sup>th</sup> & 14 <sup>th</sup> Oct 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
2 <sup>nd</sup> & 3 <sup>rd</sup> Nov 2021	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
4 <sup>th</sup> & 6 <sup>th</sup> Jan 2022	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
16 <sup>th</sup> Jan 2022	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Tullamore
22 <sup>nd</sup> & 23 <sup>rd</sup> Jan 2022	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
1 <sup>st</sup> & 3 <sup>rd</sup> Feb 2022	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Tullamore
11 <sup>th</sup> , 13 <sup>th</sup> , 15 <sup>th</sup> & 17 <sup>th</sup> Feb 2022	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Tullamore
11 <sup>th</sup> , 13 <sup>th</sup> , 15 <sup>th</sup> & 17 <sup>th</sup> March 2022	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Tullamore
22 <sup>nd</sup> , 26 <sup>th</sup> & 29 <sup>th</sup> March 2022	Medical SHO	Naas General Hospital, Co. Kildare
20 <sup>th</sup> , 26 <sup>th</sup> & 28 <sup>th</sup> April 2022	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
10 <sup>th</sup> & 17 <sup>th</sup> May 2022	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
28 <sup>th</sup> July 2022	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
10 <sup>th</sup> Sept 2022	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
11 <sup>th</sup> , 13 <sup>th</sup> & 15 <sup>th</sup> Oct 2022	Medical Registrar	Naas General Hospital, Co. Kildare
20 <sup>th</sup> Oct 2022	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Tullamore
25 <sup>th</sup> Oct 2022	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
29 <sup>th</sup> & 30 <sup>th</sup> Oct 2022	Medical Registrar	Wexford General Hospital
1 <sup>st</sup> Nov 2022	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
12 <sup>th</sup> & 13 <sup>th</sup> Nov 2022	Medical Registrar	Wexford General Hospital
17 <sup>th</sup> Nov 2022	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
25 <sup>th</sup> Nov 2022	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
26 <sup>th</sup> & 27 <sup>th</sup> Nov 2022	Medical Registrar	Wexford General Hospital
23 <sup>rd</sup> Jan 2023	Medical SHO	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
9 <sup>th</sup> Feb 2023	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
1 <sup>st</sup> March 2023	Medical Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Portlaoise
	ca.car regional	The same regional mospitum of the order
	1	l

07/2020 to Current Endocrinology Registrar and UCD Clinical Tutor

**HSE - Mullingar** — Mullingar, Westmeath

Professor Shu Hoashi, Professor Clare Fallon, Dr Ultan Healy, Dr Inam Khan

07/2019 to 07/2020 GIM/Endocrinology Registrar

**HSE - Mullingar** 

Professor Shu Hoashi ,Dr Ultan Healy Dr. Hilary Cronin, Professor Clare Fallon, Dr.

Inam Khan

09/2018 to 07/2019 Clinical Lecturer/Tutor

**University of Limerick** — Limerick, Limerick Professor Tom Kiernan, Professor Austin Stack

07/2018 to 08/2018 Medical Registrar

**HSE** — Kilkenny, Kilkenny Dr Michael Conway

08/2017 to 07/2018 GIM/Rheumatology Registrar

**LRH MTI** - Peshawar

Dr Suleman Khan Dr Zahir Shah Afridi Professor Dr Amjad taqweem

07/2016 to 07/2017 Medical Registrar

Mardan Medical Complex
Dr Amir Khan, Dr Hadi

07/2014 to 07/2016 Senior House Officer

**HSE-Mullingar** 

Professor Shu Hoashi,Dr. Hilary Cronin,Professor Clare Fallon,Dr Inam Khan,Dr Mark

Sheehy, Dr Murat Kirca

07/2011 to 07/2014 Postgraduate GIM Resident

KTH MTI

Professor Dr Noor Ul Iman, Professor Dr Hamza Khan

01/2010 to 01/2011 Intern/House Officer

**PGMI LRH** 

Professor Intekhab Alam, Professor Muzaffar saddia

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

• Retrospective national cohort study of pregnancy outcomes for women with type 1 and type 2 diabetes mellitus in Republic of Ireland Christine Newman a,\*, Aoife M. Egan b, Tomas Ahern c, Maisa Al-Kiyumi d, Siobhan Bacon e, Elgelani Bahaeldein f, Gabriela Balan d, Mary-Jane Brassill g, Emily Breslin e, Elizabeth Brosnan h, Louise Carmody a, Hilda Clarke i, Caroline Coogan Kelly j, Linda Culliney k, Recie Davern d, Maeve Durkan I, Kalthoom Elhilo m, Elizabeth Cullen d, Mairead Fenlon n, Pauline Ferry o, Ahmed Gabirf, Linda Guinan g, Geraldine Hanlon j, Marie Heffernan p, Tom Higgins q, Shu Hoashi r, Oratile Kgosidialwa k, Amjed Khamis o, Brendan Kinsley d, Breda Kirwan a, Anne James c, Pyeh Kyithar m, Aaron Liew i, Ihtisham Malik h, Linda Matthews c, Colm McGurk j, Cathy McHugh e, Yvonne Moloney s, Matt S Murphy p, Paula Murphy k, Dina

Nagodra m, Eoin Noctor s, Marie Nolan q, Aislong O'Connor o, Emily O'Connori, Domhnall O'Halloran k, Linda O'Mahoney k, Triona O'Shea f, Eoin P. O'Sullivan I, Moby Petersf, Graham Robertsf, Hannorah Rooney j, Jayant Sharma m, Aoife Smyth d, Maria Synnott m, Bheesham Tarachand f, Marie Tighe e, Marie Todd h, Michael Towersf, Antoinette Tuthill k, Wan Mahmood d, Obada Yousif n, Fidelma P. Dunne PMID: 35709911 DOI: 10.1016/j.diabres.2022.109947

- Activation of PPCI Team in the Octogenarian and Nonagenarians
   Population:Real world single centre experience. Kumar, Rajesh O'Connor,
   Cormac Kumar, Jatinder Kerr, Brain Malik, Ihtisham Homer, Ciarrai Abbas,
   Syed Arnous, Samer Ullah, Ihsan Kiernan, Thomas ( submitted online and is
   presently being given full consideration for publication in Open Heart
   manuscript ID is openhrt-2021-001709.R1)
- Young at heart: Risk factor assessment of young adults (≤45) with st elevated myocardial infarction R Kumar, J Kumar, C O'Connor, N Sankhyan, IMalik, MN Shakoor, J Zaman, E Turner, A Buckley, A Maloney, S Arnous, T Kiernan

Heart Oct 2019, 105 (Suppl 7) A36-A37; DOI: 10.1136/heartjnl-2019-ICS.46

- Progressive pseudorheumatoid dysplasia (PPRD) in siblings mimicking inflammatory arthropathy <u>I.Malik</u>, S. Khan, Z. Afridi, Ann Rheum Dis, volume 77, supplement Suppl, year 2018, page A1657 DOI: 10.1136/annrheumdis-2018-eular.4376
- Provision of rheumatology services to 30 million people in north-western
   Pakistan (A Naïve Department With Huge Challenges) <u>I.Malik</u>, S. Khan, Z.
   Afridi ) Ann Rheum Dis, volume 77, supplement Suppl, the year 2018, page A1719 DOI: 10.1136/annrheumdis-2018-eular
- Pregabalin overdose causing sinus bradycardia A rare complication Kumar R, Kumar J, Malik I, Pate G (2021) J Cardiovasc Med Cardiol 8(1): 007-009. DOI: https://dx.doi.org/10.17352/2455-2976.000160
- Frequency of dyslipidemia In Patients with sub-clinical hypothyroidism
   Dissertation submitted and accepted by College of physicians and
   surgeons Pakistan (CPSP)Pakistan.

#### **POSTER PRESENTATIONS**

- CR43 Case Series of Parathyroid Adenoma detection with 4D CT Parathyroid
   Abrar Ahmad1, Ihtisham Malik1, Ultan Healy 1, Vivek Raman3, Shu Hoashi1,2
- CR13 Severe Diabetic Gastroparesis During Pregnancy: A Case Report Ihtisham Malik1, Abrar Ahmad1, AnnMarie Keogh1, Maeve Dempsey1, Yvonne Reidy1, Murat Kirca2, Ultan Healy1, Sam Thomas3, Shu Hoashi1,4
- Glycaemic control in patients with Gestational Diabetes requiring betamethasone – a quality improvement project with intravenous insulin infusion protocol Ihtisham Malik DOI: 10.1530/endoabs.73.AEP195
- Does COVID cause diabetes? Malik I, Rafi A, Sheehy M, Healy U, Hoashi S Irish Journal of Medical Science (1971 -) (2021) 190 (Suppl 3):S77–S115 https://doi.org/10.1007/s11845-021-02557-8
- A Re-audit of basal (long-acting) insulin prescription in the management of Diabetic Ketoacidosis and its effect on length of hospital A Rafi, I Malik, B McDonnell, E Brosnan Irish Journal of Medical Science (1971 -) (2021) 190 (Suppl 3):S77–S115 https://doi.org/10.1007/s11845-021-02557-8
- An Audit of Relationship between Metformin Dosing and Micronutrients deficiency A Rafi, R Shah, I Malik, P Muthalagu Department of Medicine,

Cavan General Hospital, Cavan, Ireland Irish Journal of Medical Science (1971 -) (2021) 190 (Suppl 3):S77–S115 https://doi.org/10.1007 /s11845-021-02557-8

 Audit on glycaemic control in Gestational Diabetes Mellitus (GDM) patients receiving corticosteroids I Malik, A Rafi, U Healy, S Hoashi Irish Journal of Medical Science (1971 -) (2021) 190 (Suppl 3):S77-S115 https://doi.org /10.1007/s11845-021-02557-8

## **AUDITS/QUALITY IMPROVEMENT PROJECTS**

- Prescription of VTE prophylaxis in IBD patients at the time of admission: A quality improvement project (MRH Mullingar)
- Causes of discrepancy between thyroid ultrasound reports and FNAC results in patients with thyroid nodules(MRH Mullingar)
- Glucose Challenge test and COVID 19 Pandemic(MRH Mullingar)

#### POSTGRADUATE PRIZES AND AWARDS

4th Annual Research and Audit Day 2020 Awarded by Research and Audit Committee Awarded for best Poster Presentation in Medicine and 3rd Overall

#### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

I have gained significant teaching experience thus far in my career. I have spent 39 months as a clinical lecturer at Limerick and Mullingar and have been teaching GEMS students at Limerick and UCD / RSCI students at Mullingar. During this time I gave bedside tutorials focussing on history clinical examination and communication skills and large/small group tutorials for all medical students with emphasis on ACUTE MEDICINE and DATA interpretation

I have been delivering small group tutorial to Medical SHOs (Basic Specialist trainees plus stand alone NCHDs) preparing for their membership examinations and have been part of the rota with consultants for same

#### **SKILLS**

# Clinical Experience and Skills-General Medicine

I have worked with variety of GIM and Subspecialty consultants and gained substantial experience (FIVE years Clinical Fellowship in General Internal

Endocrinology Registrar ) in management of general medical patients encountered on unselected medical take, critically unwell medical patients and management of complex patients

## Clinical Experience and Skills -Endocrinology

I have worked with Professor Shu Hoashi and Dr Ultan Healy for the last THREE years in Endocrinology and Diabetes department and gained experience in

Medicine, THREE experience as Medical the management of disorders of the Registrar and THREE years experience as pituitary gland, salt and water disorders, disorders of the thyroid gland, calcium and bone disorders, adrenal disorders ,neuroendocrine tumours, reproductive endocrinology and management of patients with T2DM/T1DM /GDM its complications, use of existing and emerging technologies relating to the treatment of diabetes and also part of a multidisciplinary diabetes team.

## LEADERSHIP AND MANAGEMENT

As intern I was **lead intern** in Pakistan in organisation of Intern rota and teaching

activities for interns. As Fellowship trainee my main role in my second year was rota management and organisation of MDTs. In Ireland beside being part of different NCHDs committees my main role has been organisation of all teaching activities for Endocrine department in Mullingar and for UCD/RCSI undergraduate students and also for interns. I have always worked with SpRs in organisation of both departmental Journal Clubs and Hospital Grand Rounds and have always been flexible and volunteering for ONCALLS or other activities as needed I have worked with Cardiology team for the last two years and have been helping in outpatient's clinics and worked and will work to clear the backlog of patients through NTPF funding from HSE

I completed HST Leadership in Clinical Practice in Nov 2021 which was entirely focussed on management and leadership

#### **PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS**

- Member of Irish Endocrine Society
- Member of Endocrine Society
- Member of American College of Physicians (ACP)
- Member of American Associations of Clinical Endocrinologists (AACE)
- Member of European Society of Endocrinology (ESE)
- Member of European Society of Cardiology